q and on has this in my personal
experience of what I see in my community
this kind of captivating almost
seductive sensational thing going on in
the way it captures people's attention
and I'm wondering like what can we learn
about good distributed collective
intelligence from q and on and then what
should we be most cautious of when
looking at that and learning from that
that's a really good question thank you
by the way a bold question because as
you know even I think using the letter Q
these days tended to get you thrown in
jail so let's see let's think about that
so first off let's recognize that I
think the answer to the first part is a
lot I think it's naive beyond
comprehension to not recognize it that
was a very powerful valuable experience
from which we could learn a lot so what
are the some of the things that showed
up if you think about it and I was
watching it very closely for a long time
so some of the things that showed up I
would say are like cardinal virtues it's
a deep stuff that frankly has been part
of cold any culture that's worth of shit
for a long time
the phrase is like where we go one we go
all notions like own your mistakes
notions like take responsibility for
actually digging take personal
responsibility for perceiving reality
think bigger don't be trapped in
existing ideological frameworks of what
isn't what is not be aware the fact that
this information is just information is
everywhere so don't stick to any
particular point of view and soon assume
that that isn't Thoreau tative
hope community connecting with each
other helping each other and this like
you know in some sense it isn't that
complicated just to take a look at at
the mythopoetic archetypes of what
virtue and heroism and wholesomeness
have always looked like and do that and
to the degree to which the Q community
found that and upregulated that that is
the strong positive virtues that are in
fact in that community alright let's go
to the opposite direction it's weird
because it seems to hold both
simultaneously which is kind of an
interesting thing where there's
certain mania there's a certain manic
psychotic sensibility a you we live in a
psychotic age and we live in a psychotic
age because we all have the capacity to
interact with far more
information about reality then a our
minds can handle and far less
information about reality than be
actually tells us much about reality so
in an environment we can tell really
awesome stories we can weave together
narratives that sort of hold the
information that we've been able to
gather and hold into something like a
coherent story and then we try to
fact-check that by actually doing more
information this is what I think we're
the key phenomena has it's one of his
biggest gaps is it is so bound to the
virtual and it's so capable I've been
researching things at the virtual but
then tries to draw conjectures on the
basis inference and hypothesis and
models of nature and and and models
about what the underlying the axiomatic
structures of reality are and so if you
think that I don't know let's go with
something
you think there's an organization called
Rizvi 2 verse which is tied to the Saudi
royal family and they have certain
capacities and agendas then you can use
that assumption complex about which you
have no in reality to explain a very
large number of phenomena now you're
gonna get a whole bunch of anomalous
phenomena around that but you're gonna
pretend to ignore the anomalous
phenomena be really happy about the
thing that's inside your explanatory
framework which is you say the key
phenomenon gives us bas relief on the
weakness of the paradigmatic mind pull
stop it tended to be psychotic and manic
and to be self was the true bias towards
its own self referentiality
and of course we also seen a tendency a
strong tendency although not necessarily
a overwhelming tendency to engage in the
exact opposite of responsibility to
externalize to hope that someone else is
in charge and will in fact take care of
us and I believe that is also
unfortunate at the end of the day false
which is to say only this to the degree
which there are people who are in
positions of power authority
responsibility who have our best
interest in nine great awesome if we
take responsibility for ourselves with
complete integrity then their interest
in our interests would be completely
aligned so we don't need to worry about
whether they're there or not but to the
degree to which we alienate ourselves
from our own agency just sort of step
back and really hope they're doing a
good job and become cheerleaders or fans
in a sporting event and they're the team
on the field and we're the guys the
butts in the seats we've done exactly
the wrong thing